Guide to the Oscar I. Norwich Collection of Maps of Africa and Its Islands, 1486 - ca. 1865 NORWICH
David Rumsey Map Center
- Aphricae Tabula II. = Map of North Africa. -- Basel: Munster, Sebastian, 1489-1552; Munster, Sebastian, 1489-1552, 1544; NOR 0289; Woodcut: Uncolored; 25 cm. x 33 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Rivers inaccurately drawn. Legend at upper left contains all of the town names in Latin. Top left: 964. Top right: 965. Bottom right: XX5.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3671463 Page number:map 0289, p. 328
  Norwich number: 0289
  RID: MOA 0040
- Altera Generalis Tab. Secundum Ptol. = Another map according to Ptolemy. -- Basel: Munster, Sebastian, 1489-1552; Munster, Sebastian, 1489-1552, 1550; NOR 0290; Woodcut: Colored; 25 cm. x 34 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Smaller German edition of this map in Munster's Cosmographia (1550). Surrounding the earth are "billowing clouds and numerous wind gods". Another Latin title on verso.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0290, p. 329
  Norwich number: 0290
  RID: MOA 0161
- Aphricae Tabula IIII. = Map of North Africa. -- Basel: Petri, Heinrich, 1508-1579; Ptolemy, 2nd cent., 1571; NOR 0291; Woodcut: Colored; 25 cm. x 34 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: "This map is identified as a Ptolemy edition of 1571, probably by Munster." Trapezoidal projection. Title on verso: Quarta Aphricae Tabula, continent interiorem Libyam et Aethiopiam quae sub Aegypto ...
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0291, p. 330
  Norwich number: 0291
  RID: MOA 0185
- Tabula Africae IIII. = Map of Africa. -- Venice: Valgrisi, Vincenzo, fl. 1540-1572 (printer); Ptolemy, 2nd cent., 1561; NOR 0292; Copperplate: Uncolored; 18 cm. x 24 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Trapezoidal projection. Sea stippled in the Italian style. Atlas edited by Girolamo Ruscelli, d. 1565.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3671463 Page number:map 0292, p. 331
  Norwich number: 0292
  RID: MOA 0041
- The Kingedome of Congo. -- London: Wolfe, John, d. 1601; Pigafetta, Filippo, 1533-1604; Pigafetta, Filippo, 1533-1604, 1598; NOR 0293; : Uncolored; 8.5 cm. x 12 cm.
  Source: The Second Booke. The true and perfect description of the whole of Guinea, Manicongo, Angola, Monomotapa ... (1598) (English edition)
  Descriptive Notes: This map is an English translation of Johan Huygen van Linschoten's Relatione de Reame di Congo.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0293, p. 333
  Norwich number: 0293
  RID: MOA 0148
  Africa -- Congo -- 16th c.
- Medius meridianus 16, reliqui ad hunc inclinati funt pro ratione parallelorum 29 34 ad circulum maximum. = Coast of North-West Africa and part of Spain. -- Unknown: Bertius, Petrus, 1565-1629; Ptolemy, 2nd cent., 1618; NOR 0294; : Outline color; 32 cm. x 46 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: This map and NOR 0295 are marked Africae I Tab and II Tab at the top. "First appeared in the 1584 edition of Ptolemy published by Gerard Mercator". Again later in Gerard's 1778 edition.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0294, p. 334
  Norwich number: 0294
  RID: MOA 0241
  Africa -- Northern coast of Africa -- 17th c.
- Medius meridianus 37, reliqui ad hunc inclinantur ratione 28 33 parallellorum. = Mediterranean Sea and north coast of Africa from latitude 37 degrees. -- Unknown: Bertius, Petrus, 1565-1629; Ptolemy, 2nd cent., 1618; NOR 0295; : Outline color; 33 cm. x 46 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Includes southern part of Sardina and Sicily. The stippled sea contains two sea monsters. Mainland is decorated with a lion and a leopard. Similar map appears in Tabulae Geografficae Orbis Terrarum ... by Jan van Vianen (1704). Title across top: Afri II Tab.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0295, p. 335
  Norwich number: 0295
  RID: MOA 0242
- Barbaria. -- Amsterdam: Blaeu, Willem Janszoon, 1571-1638; Blaeu, Willem Janszoon, 1571-1638, 1663; NOR 0296; : Outline color; 21 cm. x 57 cm.
  Source: Le Grand Atlas (1663)
  Descriptive Notes: Two parallel maps on one sheet, 21 x 57 cm. and 26 x 57 cm. The upper map shows North Africa. The lower map illustrates an enlarged area of Barbaria. Top right: 150.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0296, p. 336
  Norwich number: 0296
  RID: MOA 0098
  Africa -- Northern Africa -- 17th c.
- In Notitiam Ecclesiasticam Africae Tabula Geographica. = Map of north coast of Africa, Spain and the Mediterranean. -- Paris: L'Isle, Guillaume de, 1675-1726; L'Isle, Guillaume de, 1675-1726; L'Isle, Guillaume de, 1675-1726, 1745; NOR 0297; : Outline color; 48.5 cm. x 64 cm.
  Source: Carte d'Afrique dresee (1722)
  Descriptive Notes: Map includes "countries bordering the Mediterranean to the north, as far as Greece."
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0297, p. 337
  Norwich number: 0297
  RID: MOA 0278
  Africa -- North Africa -- 18th c.
- Carte de l'Egypte, de Ia Nubie, de l'Abissinie. = Map of Egypt, Nubia and Abyssinia. -- Amsterdam: Covens, Jean; Mortier, Corneille; L'Isle, Guillaume de, 1675-1726, No date; NOR 0298; : Colored; 49 cm. x 57 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Companion map, see NOR 0297. Includes Horn of Africa, Arabia and a portion of Persia. Top right: 22.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0298, p. 338
  Norwich number: 0298
  RID: MOA 0227
  Africa -- Northern Africa -- 18th c.
- Deserta Aegypti, Thebaidis, Arabia, Syriae, etc. = Desert regions of Egypt, Sudan, Arabia, Syria, etc. -- Augsburg: Seutter, Matthaeus, 1678-1756; Seutter, Matthaeus, 1678-1756; Seutter, Matthaeus, 1678-1756, 1725; NOR 0299; : Colored; 49.5 cm. x 57 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Includes places of biblical interest. Also illustrated are Palestine "and places such as Jerusalem, Jericho, Ashkalond and Gaza."
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0299, p. 339
  Norwich number: 0299
  RID: MOA 0240
  Africa -- Egypt -- 18th c.
- Stauum Maroccanorum, Regnorum nempe Fessani, Maroccani, Tafiletani et Segelomessani Secundum suas Provincias accurate divisorum typus Generalis Novus ... = Morocco. -- Nurnberg: Homann, Johann Christoph, 1701-1730; Homann, Johann Christoph, 1701-1730, 1728; NOR 0300; : Colored; 48 cm. x 55 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Surrounding the title of the cartouche are four Moorish figures. Nearby a serpent, a lion and an ostrich are illustrated. Inset: Marocco and Mequinetz; Prime meridian through Tenerife.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0300, p. 340
  Norwich number: 0300
  RID: MOA 0197
  Africa -- Morocco -- 18th c.
- Partie de l'Afrique en deca de l'Equateur ... = Part of Africa north of the equator. -- Paris: Desnon, L.C.; Brion de la Tour, Louis, Not dated; NOR 0301; : Colored; 23 cm. x 25.5 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Prime meridian through Tenerife.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0301, p. 341
  Norwich number: 0301
  RID: MOA 0112
- Egypt with part of Arabia and Palestine. Compiled from the draughts of the Scientific Institute established at Cairo 1800. -- London: Robert Laurie and James Whittle; Enouy, Josh [Joseph], 1801; NOR 0302; : Colored; 65 cm. x 46 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Shows the routes of several generals, such as General Bonaparte in the years 1798 and 1799; Prime meridian through London.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0302, p. 342
  Norwich number: 0302
  RID: MOA 0158
  Africa -- Northern Africa -- 19th c.
- Cosmographo de sua Magestade. = East Indies navigational chart or 'carreira'. -- Lisbon: Teixeira, Joao (fl. 1620-1650); Teixeira, Joao (fl. 1620-1650), 1649; NOR 0305; : Uncolored; 74 cm. x 51 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Inset: Plans of Mombassa, Mozambique, Sofala and the Island of Sacatora.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0305, p. 346
  Norwich number: 0305
  RID: MOA 0309
- Carte de la Coste Orientale d'Afrique, Depuis le Cap de Bonne Esperance, Jusqu'au Cap del Gada ... Publiee par ordre de Mgr. le Comte de Maurepas. = East coast of Africa from the Cape of Good Hope to Cape Delgada. -- Paris: Hondt, Pieter de; Bellin, Jacques Nicolas, 1703-1772, 1740; NOR 0306; : Outline color; 25 cm. x 23 cm.
  Source: Histoire Generale des voyages of A.F. Prevost d'Exiles and in Bellin's atlas
  Descriptive Notes: Prime meridian through Ferro Island. The interior of the map contains few details.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3671463 Page number:map 0306, p. 347
  Norwich number: 0306
  RID: MOA 0042
- Impero del Monomotapa e Stati Vicini. = Kingdom of Monomotapa and neighboring states. -- Venice Bellin, Jacques Nicolas, 1703-1772, 1781; NOR 0307; : Uncolored; 20 cm. x 26 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: The coastline illustrates many Portuguese settlements. Silver and gold mines are shown.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0307, p. 348.
  Norwich number: 0307
  RID: MOA 0094
  Africa -- Southeast Africa -- 18th c.
- A chart of the Indian Ocean improved from the chart of M. d'Apres de Mannevillette; with the addition of a part of the Pacific Ocean, as well as of the original tracks of the principal discoverers or other navigators to India and China; and in which it has been attempted to give a chronological indication of the successive discoveries. -- London: Faden, W.; Delarochette, L.; Delarochette, L. Sea chart, 1803; NOR 0308; : Outline color; 60 cm. x 102 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Chart shows the east coast of Africa and extends eastward to include New Zealand. Inset: Anemo-hydrography of the monsoons.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0308, p. 350
  Norwich number: 0308
  RID: MOA 0305
  Oceans -- Indian Ocean -- 19th c.
- To the King's most Excellent Majestry George the Third; This chart, wtih the comparative Tracks of Ships in the different Monsoons; showing the Connection distances by sea between the principle harbours and settlements in the East Indies; is with permission most humbly dedicated by ... -- London: Robert Laurie and James Whittle; Lacam, Benjamin; Lacam, Benjamin, 1808; NOR 0309; : Uncolored; 49 cm. x 59 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Dedicated to George III. Inset: A supplemental sketch exhibiting the sea engagements in the Bay of Bengal between the English and the French from 1758-1783; Prime meridian through Madras.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0309, p. 351
  Norwich number: 0309
  RID: MOA 0312
  Oceans -- Eastern Africa -- 19th c.
- Mauritania nuova tavola. = New map of Mauritania. -- Venice: Valgrisi, Vincenzo, fl. 1540-1572 (printer); Ruscelli, Girolamo, d. ca. 1565, 1561-62; NOR 0313; Copperplate: Uncolored; 18 cm. x 24.5 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Includes engraved stippled seas and anthill mountain ranges. Italian text on verso.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3671463 Page number:map 0313, p. 357
  Norwich number: 0313
  RID: MOA 0043
  Africa -- Western Africa -- 16th c.
- Parte del Africa. = Part of Africa. -- Venice: Gastaldi, Giacomo, ca. 1500-ca. 1565; Ramusio, Giovanni Battista, 1485-1557, 1550-1559; NOR 0314; Woodcut: Uncolored; 27 cm. x 37 cm.
  Source: Ramusio's Delle Navigationi et Viaggi nel qual si Contiene les Descrittione dele Africa.
  Descriptive Notes: Interior includes mountains, trees, natives, Castel de la Mina (Portuguese fort known for exporting gold), an elephant, camel, monkey and a lion. The seas are engraved in horizontal wavy lines and are decorated with paddling canoes, sea monsters and ships. Top right: 370. Top left: 371.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0314, p. 358
  Norwich number: 0314
  RID: MOA 0137
- Guinea. -- Amsterdam: Blaeu, Willem Janszoon, 1571-1638; Blaeu, Willem Janszoon, 1571-1638, 1663; NOR 0315; : Outline color; 38 cm. x 52 cm.
  Source: Grand Atlas (1663)
  Descriptive Notes: Interior is illustrated with animals, rivers, lakes and mountains. Sea contains five ships and two compass roses with rhumb lines. Dedicated to D. Nicolao Tulp. "Tulp is the Dutch doctor who appears in Rembrandt's painting, The Anatomy Lesson."
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0315, p. 359
  Norwich number: 0315
  RID: MOA 0097
  Africa -- Western Africa -- 17th c.
- Guinae nova descriptio. = New map of Guinea. -- Amsterdam: Hondius, Jodocus, 1563-1612; Hondius, Jodocus, 1563-1612, 1606; NOR 0316; : Uncolored; 34 cm. x 49 cm.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0316, p. 360
  Norwich number: 0316
  RID: MOA 0267
  Africa -- Guinea -- 17th c.
- Carte de la Barbarie, le la Nigritie et de la Guinee. = Map of Barbary, Nigeria and Guinea. -- Paris: L'Isle, Guillaume de, 1675-1726; L'Isle, Guillaume de, 1675-1726, 1700-1712; NOR 0317; : Colored; 49 cm. x 57 cm.
  Source: Atlas de Geographie (1700-1712)
  Descriptive Notes: Interior contains large amount of geographical information; Prime meridian through Ferro Island.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0317, p. 362
  Norwich number: 0317
  RID: MOA 0226
  Africa -- Western Africa -- 18th c.
- Guinea. -- London: Ogilby, John, 1600-1676; Ogilby, John, 1600-1676, 1671; NOR 0318; : Colored; 26 cm. x 36 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: The cartouche contains an oval-shapped title surrounded by angels. Interior contains small animals and towns. A partial compass rose radiates rhumb lines. Calligraphy appears similar to Blaeu.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0318, p. 363
  Norwich number: 0318
  RID: MOA 0162
- Carte Nouvelle de la Mer du Sud, Dressee par ordre des principaux Directeurs et tiree des Memoires les plus recents ... = Map of the Southern Oceans. -- Amsterdam: Leth, Andries de, 1662-1731; Leth, Hendrik de; Leth, Andries de, 1662-1731; Leth, Hendrik de, 1730; NOR 0320; Copperplate: Colored; 57 cm. x 94 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: "Extends from the western half of Africa in the east to the East Indies in the west." California is shown as an island. Title across top: Nova mona Pacfic tabula ... Inset: Straits of Gibralter. Cape of Good Hope. Mexico City. Panama. Bay of Porto Bello. Scenes from the French Islands. Bay of Rio de Janeiro. Vera Cruz and Havana; Prime meridian through Ferro Island.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0320, p. 366
  Norwich number: 0320
  RID: MOA 0277
- Coste Occidentale d'Afrique depuis le XIe degre de Latitude Meridionale, jusqu'au cap de Bonne Esperance ... Publiee par ordre de Mgr. le Comte de Maurepas. = West coast of Africa from 11degrees to the Cape of Good Hope. -- Paris: Bellin, Jacques Nicolas, 1703-1772; Bellin, Jacques Nicolas, 1703-1772, 1739; NOR 0321; : Outline color; 25 cm. x 26.5 cm.
  Source: Histoire Generale des voyages of A.F. Prevost d'Exiles
  Descriptive Notes: A map illustrating the southeastern conterpart, see NOR 0306. Top right: Afrique Occidentale No. 3.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0321, p. 368
  Norwich number: 0321
  RID: MOA 0088
- A new and accurate map of Negroland and the Adjacent Countries; also Upper Guinea showing the principal European Settlements, and distinguishing those belonging to England, Denmark and Holland. The Sea Coast and some of the Rivers being drawn from Surveys and the best modern Maps and Charts ... -- London: Bowen, Emanuel, d. 1767; Bowen, Emanuel, d. 1767, 1747; NOR 0322; : Colored; 24 cm. x 42 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: "Includes the Gold, Tooth, Grain and Slave Coasts of West Africa." Prime meridian through London. Bottom left: No. 56.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0322, p. 369
  Norwich number: 0322
  RID: MOA 0105
- Bowles's New Pocket map of the Coast of Africa, from Sta. Cruz ... to Angola ... with explanatory notes and a correct chart of the Gold Coast. -- London: Bowles, Carington, 1724-1793; Bowles, Carington, 1724-1793, 1752; NOR 0323; : Colored; 49 cm. x 57 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: A descriptive panel states historic and topographic details. Inset: A Correct Chart of the Gold Coast according to the Sr. Danville on a larger scale (scale in British and French sea leagues).
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0323, p. 370
  Norwich number: 0323
  RID: MOA 0109
- Carte Reduite de L'ocean Meridional ... = Map of the southern ocean. -- Paris: Bellin, Jacques Nicolas, 1703-1772; Bellin, Jacques Nicolas, 1703-1772, 1753; NOR 0324; : Uncolored; 54 cm. x 86 cm.
  Source: Neptune Francais (1753)
  Descriptive Notes: Numerous rhumb lines extend over the southwest coast of Africa and South America. Prime meridian through Paris, Tenerife, Cap Lezard, London and Ferro Island.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0324, p. 371
  Norwich number: 0324
  RID: MOA 0089
  Africa -- Southern oceans -- 18th c.
- An Accurate Map of the Coast of Cape de Verde. -- London: Kitchin, Thomas, d. 1784; Kitchin, Thomas, d. 1784; Kitchin, Thomas, d. 1784, 1765; NOR 0325; : Uncolored; 22 cm. x 14 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Inset: Cape Emanuel and Goree Island. Bottom left: No. 49. Bottom right: Plate XXVII. Vol. 2 p. 245.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0325, p. 372
  Norwich number: 0325
  RID: MOA 0129
  Africa -- Cape Verde -- 18th c.
- The Western Coast of Africa from Cape Blanco to Cape Virga, Exhibiting Senigambia Proper. -- London: Sayer, Robert, 1725-1794; Jefferys, Thomas, d. 1771, 1789; NOR 0326; : Colored; 71 cm. x 52 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Note: "This map is copied from an original drawn by Mons. d'Anville at the expense of the French East India Company and published at Paris in 1751. But since the Peace of 1762 that Map has been supressed. The Country through which the R. Senegal runs has been improved corrected from a large curious survey of the river found in the fort of Senegal"; Prime meridian through Ferro Island.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0326, p. 373
  Norwich number: 0326
  RID: MOA 0313
- Coast of Africa from the Straits of Gilbraltar to Cabo Verde ... -- London: Cadell Davies; Arrowsmith, Aaron, 1750-1823; Arrowsmith, Aaron, 1750-1823, 1803; NOR 0328; : Uncolored; 112 cm. x 25.5 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Part of a series of four double-page coastal maps, (see NOR 227, NOR 0329, NOR 0330, NOR 0331). Coastline contains soundings; Prime meridian through Greenwich. Top right: Chart 1.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0328, p. 375
  Norwich number: 0328
  RID: MOA 0080
  Africa -- West Coast of Africa -- 19th c.
- Coast of Africa from Cabo Verde to Cabo Formosa ... -- London: Cadell Davies; Arrowsmith, Aaron, 1750-1823; Arrowsmith, Aaron, 1750-1823, 1803; NOR 0329; : Uncolored; 25.5 cm. x 40.5 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Insets: Kingdom of Kayor (scale of maine leagues) and Coastline from Rio Nuno to Illia dos Idolos (with a scale of marine leagues); Prime meridian through Greenwich. Top right: Chart 2.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0329, p. 376
  Norwich number: 0329
  RID: MOA 0082
- Calabar and Bonny Rivers. From an Original Survey by Capt. William Newton, Late of the Port of Bristol, communicated by Mr Pocock. -- London: Cadell Davies; Newton, William; Newton, William, 1803; NOR 0330; : Uncolored; 26 cm. x 20.5 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Guide to the west coast estuaries." Numerous soundings, bars and breakers are stated. The interior indicates places such as, Rough Corner, Yam Town and an English burial-place. Title across the top: Western Coast of Africa. Illustrative Chart 1.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0330, p. 377
  Norwich number: 0330
  RID: MOA 0130
  Africa -- Western Coast of Africa -- 19th c.
- Coast of Africa from Cabo Formosa to the Cabo de Boa Esperaca. -- London: Cadell Davies; Arrowsmith, Aaron, 1750-1823; Arrowsmith, Aaron, 1750-1823, 1803; NOR 0331; : Uncolored; 41 cm. x 25.5 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Inset: Cabo de Santa Catherina and St. Elena Bay (scale in one league); Prime meridian through Greenwich. Top right: Chart 3.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0331, p. 378
  Norwich number: 0331
  RID: MOA 0083
- [Aden, Mombaza, Quiloa, Cefala]. -- Cologne: Braun, Georg, 1540 or 1-1622; Hogenberg, Franz d. 1590?; Braun, Georg, 1540 or 1-1622; Hogenberg, Franz d. 1590?; Braun, Georg, 1540 or 1-1622; Hogenberg, Franz d. 1590?, 1572; NOR 0332; Copperplate: Colored; 47 cm. x 32 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Map illustrates four views of ports and harbours of the east coast of Africa.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0332, p. 380
  Norwich number: 0332
  RID: MOA 0110
  Africa -- East coast of Africa -- 16th c.
- S. Lorenzo. = Madagascar. -- Venice: Porcacchi, Thomaso, 1530-1585? (printer); Porcacchi, Thomaso, 1530-1585?; Porcacchi, Thomaso, 1530-1585?, 1590; NOR 0333; : Uncolored; 22 cm. x 14 cm.
  Source: L'Isole Piu Famose del Mondo (1590) (2nd. edition)
  Descriptive Notes: "First appeared in 1572, and various editions appeared up to 1686." The seas contain a compass rose and two sea monsters. Italian text below map. Title across the top: Descrittione dell'Isola di S. Lorenzo. Top left: 178.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3671463 Page number:map 0333, p. 381
  Norwich number: 0333
  RID: MOA 0044
  Islands -- Madagascar -- 16th c.
- Insula Madagascar alias S. Laurentii dicta: huius Conditio. = Madagascar. -- London: Bry, Theodor de, 1528-1598; Bry, Theodor de, 1528-1598; Bry, Theodor de, 1528-1598, 1590-1634; NOR 0334; : Uncolored; 14 cm. x 20 cm.
  Source: Petits Voyages
  Descriptive Notes: Map also appeared in "Pieter Willemsz's and Verhoefs Voyage to the Moluccas 1607-1609, first published in Frankfurt-am-Main in 1612 entitled Indiae Orientalis, part IX."
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3671463 Page number:map 0334, p. 382
  Norwich number: 0334
  RID: MOA 0045
- Carte de l'Isle Madagascar dite autrement Madecase et de S. Laurens et aujord'hui L'Isle Dauphine avecque les costes de Cofala et du Mozambique en Afrique. = Map of Madagascar ... and the coast of Mozambique. -- Paris: Duval, P. (Pierre), 1619-1682; Duval, P. (Pierre), 1619-1682, 1666; NOR 0335; : Outline color; 37 cm. x 56 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: Illustrates "sea routes from the west coast of Africa to Mozambique and from Fort Dauphin on the southeast coast of Madagascar to the north, south, and to the east, to India, Surate and Malacca."
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0335, p. 384
  Norwich number: 0335
  RID: MOA 0195
  Islands -- Madagascar -- 17th c.
- Insula S. Lavrentii, vulgo Madagascar. = The Island of Madagascar. -- Amsterdam: Blaeu, Joan, 1596-1673; Blaeu, Joan, 1596-1673, 1666; NOR 0336; : Colored; 42 cm. x 55 cm.
  Source: Grand Atlas
  Descriptive Notes: The rectangular-shaped title of the cartouche is surrounded by natives, birds, sheep and a chameleon. Map Iincludes islands near Madagascar. The sea is decorated with several ships and two compass roses with rhumb lines.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0336, p. 385
  Norwich number: 0336
  RID: MOA 0099
- Carte de l'Ile de Madagascar dite aujourd'hui i'Ile Daufine. = Map of the island of Madagascar called Dauphine Island. -- Amsterdam: Chatelain, Henri Abraham; Chatelain, Henri Abraham, 1719; NOR 0337; : Colored; 36 cm. x 43.5 cm.
  Descriptive Notes: "The margins are illustrated in color with eleven descriptive vignettes of the dress, the events and the life of the inhabitants." French text below map describes the people of Madagascar and the topography. Title across top: Carte de I'Ile de Madagascar contenent sa description et diverses particularitez curieuses de ses habitans tant blanc que negres. Top right: Tom. VI No. 34 Pag. 142.
  References: Norwich (2nd ed.), ckey = 3871463 Page number:map 0337, p. 386
  Norwich number: 0337